campaignlive.com 2018-12-28

# Global privacy policy

**US Privacy Policy**

Haymarket Media Inc. ("Haymarket") has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to protect your privacy and to fully disclose what information we collect and how we use it. Please note your use of our Digital Offering is also governed by the Terms and Conditions.

**Information Collection and Dissemination**

**General Principles**

  * In general, you may visit this site or use the companion mobile applications (collectively referred to as the "Digital Offering") without identifying yourself or revealing any Personal Information.
  * As you browse our Digital Offering, the Digital Offering collects log file, IP address of your computer, and other standard tracking data we use to evaluate Digital Offering traffic and usage patterns. Such information is aggregated with tracking data from all Digital Offering visitors. We will use the information to personalize the Digital Offering according to your preferences based on the aggregated information. We also use the aggregated information to evaluate products and services we may offer to you and share it with third party advertisers and sponsors so that they may provide more tailored product offerings.
  * Some portions of this Digital Offering may require you to give us personally identifiable information such as your name, job title, company, physical mailing address, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers (Personal Information) and, if applicable, financial information such as your credit card information (Financial Information), for, without limitation, (i) registration for attendance at certain Haymarket trade shows, conferences and events; and (ii) subscriptions to our publications.
  * If you communicate with us by e-mail, post messages to any of our chat groups, bulletin boards or forums, or otherwise complete online forms, surveys or contest entries, any information provided in such communications may be collected as Personal Information.
  * If you elect to provide us with Personal Information, we use it primarily to deliver the service you requested. In order to deliver our services we may append information provided to us by third parties to help us provide you with a more relevant user experience.
  * Other uses of Personal Information are described elsewhere in this Policy.
  * If you submit Financial Information, we use that information primarily to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, registrations etc.
  * Haymarket uses a third party to process credit card transactions and does not store financial information, such as credit card information on its websites. For some transactions, we will retain the last four digits of the credit card number solely for customer service purposes.

**Information usage**

We will use your information for the following purposes:

  * to provide you with the products and services you have requested and to communicate with you about those products and services
  * to design additional services or products for customers' use
  * to let you know about any products or services which we believe may be of interest to you. You will always be able to unsubscribe or opt-out of receiving these messages
  * to work with our business partners, sponsors, advertisers and affiliates to provide you with information you have selected or that we feel may be of interest to you Unsubscribing is easy if the information is no longer useful to you. These arrangements help us to provide some of our services for free
  * to invite you to participate in sponsored informational programs
  * to provide you with advertisements, promotions or sponsored content based on information connected to your personally identifiable information such as your profession and specialty
  * invite you to share your opinions and comments
  * to conduct surveys and/or market research
  * purposes related to any of the above or as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy

**Information Sharing**

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information and your Financial Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with a court order or other legal process; (b) protect our rights or property; or (c) enforce our terms of service.

Unless you opt-out, we may share your Personal Information with Haymarket's affiliates, partners and third parties licensed or permitted to access your Personal Information by any of the foregoing.

We may share information about your engagement with any of our services including receipt and/or action with our emails, activity on our sites including content and/or advertisements viewed and actions taken or personal information otherwise provided by you.

We may invite you to participate in industry-sponsored programs which present you with branded sponsor-selected materials to provide clinical information to physicians about medical conditions, options for treatment and recommended products. Your invitation will use the Personal Information that you have provided or that we have obtained from third parties, and non-personally identifiable information which we gather from your site visits by the use of cookies or other tracking technologies. Sponsor programs will be affiliated with your area of specialty and any specific interests you have shared with us. Not everyone will qualify for an invitation to participate; conversely you may be invited to register or participate in more than one program. Haymarket will provide information, personally identified information or in aggregated form, about your participation in specific programs to the program sponsor or their representatives. This helps our industry sponsors to improve clinical education and information and communicate with you in a more targeted way. If you interact with any of our sponsors directly, their Privacy Policy and practices will apply.

We will share your Personal Information with our third party suppliers who need to process you data to deliver the services you have requested or consented to receive. These suppliers are required under contract not to use Personal Information supplied by us other than to provide the services requested by us and to guarantee to our satisfaction that they have sufficient processes in place to ensure the security of your data whilst it is in their care. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Information with our contractors and third party service supplies for the purpose of providing services to you.

Haymarket will share user data with the accredited provider(s) of CME/CE activities in which users participate, and/or medical education and communications companies who assisted in the development of CME/CE activities in which users participate.

In order to comply with the Federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, we also may provide lists of customers who have opted-out of email promotion for Haymarket products to other companies, so they can be suppressed from mailings those companies send on Haymarket's behalf. In addition, if you unsubscribe from a mailing we send to our own list on behalf of a third party, your removal instruction may also be supplied to the third party and added to their own suppression file. If you continue receiving email after opting out, please contact us at [ custserve@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserve@haymarketmedia.com)

**Aggregated information**

We sometimes provide aggregated usage or tracking information collected from this Digital Offering to third parties.

**Information on Children**

As a business-to-business company, we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. On-line registration and Digital Offering usage is restricted to adults who are professionally engaged in the businesses we serve.

**Updating Visitor Information:**

You have the option of accessing, correcting, updating and modifying your Personal and/or Financial Information, or visitor profile, at any time and as often as desired. If you desire to delete your Personal and/or Financial Information please contact us at  [ custserve@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserve@haymarketmedia.com)

**Update Your Newsletter Subscriptions**

You can opt-in to newsletter mailing lists, or remove yourself (opt-out) at any time through the subscription management page (this page will display all of your newsletter subscriptions) or by following the instructions at the end of the newsletters you receive. Please allow 3-5 business days for changes to take effect. You can locate the subscription management page through the "Log In" link at the top right hand corner of the Digital Offering. For Haymarket Digital Offerings not offering the subscription management page, please send your email preferences to [ custserv@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserv@haymarketmedia.com)

**Update Your Print Subscription Information**

You can correct or change your print subscription information by sending an email to [ custserve@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserve@haymarketmedia.com)  After processing your change will take effect with the next available issue.

**Third Party and Affiliated Links:**

Our Digital Offerings contain external links to other Digital Offerings including suppliers, advertisers and affiliates. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the content of, or information gathered by, these other Digital Offerings. We do not endorse any of these Digital Offerings or the products or services associated with such Digital Offerings merely because they are linked to our Digital Offering.

**Google:**

Haymarket uses all features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers. Google Analytics does not store any visitor specific data and we will not use visitor specific data in any way related to Google Analytics, Google Adwords, and Remarketing. Haymarket uses remarketing with Google Adwords and analytics to display content specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited our site when those visitors go to other websites that have the Google Display Network implemented. Haymarket and other third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on visitors past visits to our website. Visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers and opt out of customized Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager at  [ www.google.com/ads/preferences/ ](http://www.dmnews.com/privacypolicy/www.google.com/ads/preferences/) .

**Haymarket Magazines, Seminars, Events, Sites and Other Publications and Services**

Unless you have opted out, as a Haymarket customer you can also expect to receive relevant offers, including offers via email, telephone and/or other channels, for Haymarket publications, seminars, events, Digital Offerings and other services. From time to time we are also able to secure and offer to our customers specially-negotiated discounts and new products from other leading companies. If you would prefer not to receive such offers in the future, you can change your preference via the subscription management page which can be located by using the "Log In" link at the top right hand corner of the Digital Offering. For Haymarket Digital Offerings not offering the subscription management page, please send your email preferences to  [ custserv@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserv@haymarketmedia.com)

**Haymarket Live and Online Events**

Haymarket events are produced for a variety of companies (Sponsors). All data collected during the registration of such events may be shared with those Sponsors. This data is governed by the individual Sponsor's privacy policy and may be used by the Sponsor for follow-up purposes. Please visit the Sponsor's website to review its privacy policy. Similarly, Haymarket events will have the same access to this data as the Sponsors, and this Privacy Policy continues to govern how Haymarket uses the data. For details on how event Sponsors use the information you provide, please contact the Sponsor directly. If you have any questions, please contact [ custserv@haymarketmedia.com ](mailto:custserv@haymarketmedia.com)

**Social Rewards Program**

A number of Haymarket's sites have online social rewards programs. Registering to an applicable site automatically enrolls you in these programs. Any applicable site activity can be published in the various activity leaderboards. If you would prefer not to have your activity published you can change this by selecting the Settings button within the leaderboard and de-selecting the 'Publish Activity' tickbox.

**Online Ad Serving**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Digital Offering. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this Digital Offering and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here:  [ http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp)

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is a bit of data sent by a website through the browser to the computer of the user visiting the site, and enables the site to return the results the browser expects. Haymarket uses temporary, session-specific cookies to ensure visits to its website are smooth and customized for the visitor. Such cookies allow us to provide a visitor's browser with information tailored to the visitor's preferences and needs. Haymarket also uses permanent or persistent cookies that remain on a visitor's computer after the visitor leaves a Haymarket website.

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can turn off the cookie acceptance option in the browser's settings. However, disabling the cookie support function of the browser will prevent our website from functioning properly and you may not be able to utilize fully all of the site's features and information.

We use advertising companies to develop banner ads for our Digital Offering. These ads may contain cookies. These companies collect cookies sent to your browser through the banner ads and we do not have control or access to this data. Information may be collected from a third party through the use of cookies and web beacons to measure website traffic.

Notwithstanding any other provision, we may also engage a data provider who may collect web log data from you (including IP address and information about your browser or operating system), or place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads or content. These cookies contain no personally identifiable information. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these data provider cookies, please go to  [ http://www.aboutads.info/choices ](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

**Pixel Tags**

Like many websites, Haymarket may also use pixel tags, also known as beacons, spotlight tags or web bugs, to improve our understanding of site traffic, visitor behavior, and response to promotional campaigns, as a supplement to our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement. Pixel tags are sometimes used in conjunction with small Javascript-based applications, also for the purpose of traffic measurement. We may also implement pixel tags provided by other companies, for the same purpose. You can disable pixel tags by changing your browser settings to omit images and disable Javascript; or there are commercial software packages available that can omit pixel tags and most advertisements.

**Sale and purchase of assets**

We may buy or sell assets. If we are selling an asset or assets, including website (s) which are acquired by another company, personal, usage and financial information may be transferred as part of the change of ownership.

**Opt-out Option**

Visitors to this Digital Offering can decide if they want to receive promotional information from Haymarket. On the visitor registration pages, prospective visitors can choose to request Haymarket not to e-mail them advertising and promotional information. Should visitors accept promotional e-mail from Haymarket, any e-mail they receive will include instructions on how to be removed from Haymarket's promotional e-mail list. If you continue receiving email after opting out, please contact us at  [ custserv@haymarketmedia.com ](http://www.dmnews.com/privacypolicy/custserv@haymarketmedia.com)

**Security and Encryption**

This Digital Offering takes commercially reasonable precautions to protect your information. When appropriate, we use SSL encryption technology on our Digital Offering and a secure server to encrypt information transmitted between your browsers and our server. As a result, data you submit to our Digital Offering such as credit card and payment information is transmitted using commercially reasonable security over the Internet.

This Digital Offering also uses password encryption to keep ensure your privacy when registering for newsletters, events, and other Haymarket related media.

**Notification of Changes**

Haymarket reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Digital Offering. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Digital Offering. Please check back often to review the latest version of our Privacy Policy.

**Your Acceptance of these Terms**

By using our Digital Offering, products or services, you signify your acceptance of the terms of the Haymarket Privacy Policy and our practices in relation to the collection, use and disclosure of the information you provide or that we collect from other sources, as described in this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions. If you do not agree to the terms of the Haymarket Privacy Policy, please do not use the Digital Offering, products and/or services and exit the Digital Offering immediately.

**Questions?**

If you have any questions on our Privacy Policy, or questions about our handling of your Personal and/or Financial Information, you can contact us at  [ web@haymarketmedia.com ](http://www.dmnews.com/privacypolicy/web@haymarketmedia.com)  or write to us:

**Haymarket Media, Inc  
275 7th Avenue, New York, NY 10011  
10th Floor  
** **New York, NY 10011**
